CESAR KYLE CASIL

Software Developer

Santa Clara, CA 95054 | cesarkylecasil@gmail.com

github.com/ccasil | linkedin.com/in/ckcasil | cesarkylecasil.pink

SUMMARY

I am a Computer Science major practicing full stack development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js). I have experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. My primary goal is to contribute my passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on my technical skills.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley

Apr 2018

- Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development
 - Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding
 experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 $\textbf{Programming Languages:} \ \, \text{JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, Python, C, L} \\ \text{$^{\text{L}}$} \text{T_{E}} \text{X} \\ \text{X} \\ \text{T_{E}} \text{X} \\ \text{X}$

Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Request/Response

Database: SQL (MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js, Django ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks & Libraries: Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask

Development Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services (EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Miscellaneous: Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures, Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Ian 2018 - Present

- Building Full-Stack, modern, responsive web applications for clients while providing quick feedback and support
- Managed a small team to work with clients to create websites for various needs

Research Intern, MissionU, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017 - May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

Android Developer Intern, Garcon LLC, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

- Programmed Garcon's Android application using Android Studio and Java during early stages
- Rewrote the UI layout as well as updated deprecated code

PROJECTS

Love Changing the World, INC. - <u>http://lovechangingtheworld.org/</u>

Jun 2018 - Oct 2018

- Managed a small team to work with client, LCTW, to create a website for their non-profit organization
- Guests to website can view current and past events held by organization as well as sign up to be a volunteer or sponsor
- Supporters may donate to the organization via PayPal and receive various items of clothing as gifts depending on donation amount
- Technologies Used: React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API

Gym Log — github.com/ccasil/GymLog

Apr 2018

- Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.
- Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

Baskin Robbins Birthday 31 — github.com/ccasil/BRB31

Feb 2018

- Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.
- Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS & AFFILIATIONS

Lambda Phi Epsilon, Santa Cruz, CA

Mar 2014 - Jun 2016